Pavel Kolesnikov

Mobile: +7 926 490 91 75 Github: kolesnikov-pasha Email: olpyhn@gmail.com LinkedIn: Pavel Kolesnikov

ABOUT ME

I can offer Android Development expertise and a high motivation to help reach business goals. My goal for the next few years of my career is to grow as a manager and engineer and develop revolutionary products.

Also, I deeply understand machine learning methods and research in the field of natural language processing and ML for code. I am interested in algorithms and data structures, participate in programming competitions, and love to apply my knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

Neiro.ai

Android Team Lead and software engineer at Gleesent

Tbilisi, Georgia Aug. 2022 - Present

Android Kotlin Management

I lead a team of 4 engineers. My responsibilities include:

- o features development
- o tasks prioritizing
- synchronization with the company management
- hypotheses testing

Here are some of my recent projects:

- Retention boost: I lead the process of exploring new ways to increase the app's retention.
- o **Templates uploader**: the ability to upload custom video templates to the app.
- Sign in/sign up: the ability to sign in/sign up into the app via the phone number or Google/Apple account.
- Video revoice: UI and business logic of video revoice feature. It uses processing servers (through gRPC API) and an on-device post-processing.

Neiro.ai

Tbilisi, Georgia

Jan. 2022 - Aug. 2022

• Software engineer at Gleesent

Android Kotlin C++ MNN CI/CD Application architecture UI testing Python Firebase gRPC

I was responsible for developing features for the android version the Overdub app. For example, I deployed and optimized DL networks inferences for android devices (First Order Motion model made by our CV team and Voice Conversion model made by our Speech team).

Biganto Moscow, Russia
Software engineer Nov. 2022 - Dec. 2022

Android Kotlin C++

Worked upon application for 3D reconstruction of buildings and interiors

Yandex Moscow, Russia

Software Engineer, android developer in Yandex. Keyboard and Yandex. Translator

(Android) (Java) (Kotlin) (C++) (JNI) (SWIG) (Application architecture) (OkHTTP) (Yandex. AppMetrica)

Aug. 2019 - Oct. 2021

Projects in Yandex.Translator:

• Live Camera Translation (video captions): I developed a video-stream processing pipeline and optimized the performances of UI and processing logic. As a result, I achieved 30 FPS on modern devices and the developed module has been included in the Smart Camera feature in Yandex app.

Projects in Yandex.Keyboard:

- Settings synchronization: embedded Yandex. Passport service into the application. Implemented storing and downloading application settings in the Yandex cloud-storage. Created an algorithm for setting synchronization and developed all UI elements for this system in close connection with the design team.
- Theme builder: developed a system for automatic UI elements backgrounds, colors and size customization.
- o Built-in translator: redesigned an existing feature in Yandex.Keyboard.
- o Clipboard manager: fully developed UI elements and business-logic within a built-in clipboard manager.
- Navigation refactoring: collaborated with a designer to develop a new navigation system for the application. Implemented and deployed this system based on A/B testing results. As a result of this, clipboard manager and translator usage metrics increased by 5-10%.
- Yandex.Keyboard for Android TV: developed a new build variant of the application with a custom design and additional navigation abilities.
- Voice input: took part in the full redesign of the voice input feature twice. In the second iteration, me and the ML team of
 application added voice commands.
- o One-hand mode: developed UI elements and business-logic of a one-hand mode for Yandex.Keyboard.

Croc, IT-solutions School accelerator

• Mentor

Java Android Firebase Git Mentorship Public speaking

Moscow, Russia Sep. 2018 - May 2019

I participated in the training and mentoring of teams of schoolchildren, thanks to which, as a result, many of these teams created a working IT solution for their schools/local communities.

Croc Software engineer intern, Telegram bot development Moscow, Russia Jul. 2018 - Sep. 2018

Java Telegram API Firebase HTML

I created a Telegram bot for duty schedule management for the hardware engineers team (10-15 engineers). The bot functions included secure engineer's schedule providing, visualization of team schedule (using HTML and Java HTML rendering library) and processing commands with typos. After finishing, the team used the bot for **three years**.

EDUCATION

HSE University

Moscow, Russia

Sept. 2019 - Jul. 2023

- Bachelor Degree in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science

 Department: Applied Mathematics and Computer Science
- o Major: Machine Learning and Applications. Advanced Math class
- **About university**: Top-1 Russian University in CWTS Leiden Ranking: Computer Science and Math field. Top-72 in QS World University Rankings by Subject 2022: Computer Science Information Systems.

Programming Skills

- Languages: Kotlin, Java, Python, C++, Bash.
- Frameworks and libraries: Android SDK, Android Jetpack, MVVM, JNI, SWIG, OkHTTP, RxJava, Dagger, Kotlin Coroutines, Retrofit, MNN, Koin, Numpy, Pandas, PyTorch, UI Automator, gRPC.
- Tools and knowledge: Algorithms, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Git, CI/CD.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Yet Another Mobile Party

Moscow, Russia 24 Apr., 2021

Speaker

My colleague and I delivered a speech about battery saving techniques in Yandex. Keyboard and advanced ML solutions for typo predictions. My role in this event was to answer android-related questions and to prepare a presentation of the application.

Math, Programming and Physics olympiads

Russia/World 2017-2019

Prize-winner

- o Moscow Programming Olympiad (2nd prize)
- o Moscow Math Olympiad (3rd prize)
- o United Cross-university Math Olympiad (1st prize)
- o Bauman University Olympiad in Informatics (1st prize)
- o Bauman University Olympiad in Math (1st prize)
- o Bauman University Olympiad in Physics (2nd prize)
- Region-level stage of All-Russian Olympiad in Math (2nd prize)
- o Region-level stage of All-Russian Olympiad in Programming (2nd prize)
- o Region-level stage of All-Russian Olympiad in Physics (2nd prize)

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Android Development Course, HSE Lyceum

Moscow, Russia Oct. 2020 - May 2021

(Lecturer) (Seminars teacher)

Created program for high school students in field of Android development. 10 students had finished it.